Guys, a rocket is about to hit the moon
at seven times the speed of sound.
Because over a year ago, this SpaceX
rocket launched carrying a pair of lunar
landers, one of which made it to the
moon. And when you hear about SpaceX
landing rockets, they're talking about
the booster. But this is the upper
stage, the part that continued into
space and dropped off those landers. For
missions that end in low Earth orbit,
like dropping off satellites, the upper
stage saves up enough fuel to burn up
safely in our atmosphere after. But for
deep space missions, it uses all of its
fuel just to get there and then it gets
left in an unstable orbit. This isn't
just SpaceX. Other empty upper stages
from NASA and China and others have hit
the moon and this one is expected to
create an explosion equivalent to three
tons of TNT and a crater up to 30 m
wide, which orbiters from NASA and South
Korea are going to watch closely because
as we plan to send humans to the moon,
it's really important to understand
impacts to keep astronauts safe. to see
what happens. Subscribe.